{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": {
        "theme": [
          {
            "Question": "What year did The Beatles officially disband?",
            "TrueAnswer": "1970",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "1969",
              "1971",
              "1973"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Beatles disbanded in 1970 due to internal conflicts and creative differences among the band members."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is known as the 'King of Pop'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Michael Jackson",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Elvis Presley",
              "Prince",
              "Justin Timberlake"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Michael Jackson earned the title 'King of Pop' due to his groundbreaking contributions to music and his iconic status in the industry."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What song holds the record for most weeks at number one on Billboard Hot 100?",
            "TrueAnswer": "\"Old Town Road\" by Lil Nas X",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "\"Despacito\" by Luis Fonsi",
              "\"I Will Always Love You\" by Whitney Houston",
              "\"One Sweet Day\" by Mariah Carey and Boyz II Men"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Lil Nas X's \"Old Town Road\" achieved a record 19 weeks at number one on the Billboard Hot 100 chart."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which artist won the first season of American Idol?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Kelly Clarkson",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Carrie Underwood",
              "Adam Lambert",
              "Jennifer Hudson"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Kelly Clarkson made history by winning the inaugural season of American Idol in 2002, launching her successful music career."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the best-selling girl group of all time?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Spice Girls",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Destiny's Child",
              "TLC",
              "Fifth Harmony"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Spice Girls became the best-selling girl group with their chart-topping hits and worldwide cultural impact during the 1990s."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which rock band released the album 'The Dark Side of the Moon'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Pink Floyd",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Led Zeppelin",
              "The Rolling Stones",
              "The Who"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Dark Side of the Moon' is Pink Floyd's acclaimed eighth studio album, known for its progressive rock and conceptual themes."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What genre is Ariana Grande known for?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Pop",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "R&B",
              "Hip-hop",
              "Country"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Ariana Grande is recognized for her impressive vocal range and her contributions to the pop music genre."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which iconic artist performed the halftime show at Super Bowl XLVI?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Madonna",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Beyoncé",
              "Lady Gaga",
              "Katy Perry"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Madonna's electrifying performance at Super Bowl XLVI showcased her enduring influence on pop culture and music."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the only musician to win the Nobel Prize in Literature?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Bob Dylan",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Paul McCartney",
              "Joni Mitchell",
              "Bruce Springsteen"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Bob Dylan was awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature in 2016 for his poetic and influential songwriting."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which city is considered the birthplace of Motown Records?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Detroit",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Los Angeles",
              "New York City",
              "Memphis"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Detroit, Michigan, holds the distinction as the founding city of Motown Records, a renowned hub for soul and R&B music."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who wrote and released the song 'Purple Haze'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Jimi Hendrix",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Eric Clapton",
              "Jimmy Page",
              "Eddie Van Halen"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Jimi Hendrix, an influential guitarist, wrote and performed 'Purple Haze' as a pivotal track in the history of rock music."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which rapper is known as 'Slim Shady'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Eminem",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Dr. Dre",
              "Notorious B.I.G.",
              "Snoop Dogg"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Eminem's alter ego 'Slim Shady' emerged in his early career, representing his edgier and provocative artistic persona."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which country music legend released the hit song 'Jolene'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Dolly Parton",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Loretta Lynn",
              "Tammy Wynette",
              "Patsy Cline"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Dolly Parton, an iconic figure in country music, composed and popularized the timeless classic 'Jolene' in 1973."
          },
          {
            "Question": "In which year did Elvis Presley receive his first Grammy Award?",
            "TrueAnswer": "1967",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "1958",
              "1961",
              "1972"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Elvis Presley earned his first Grammy Award in 1967 for Best Sacred Performance with his album 'How Great Thou Art.'"
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the lead vocalist of the rock band Queen?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Freddie Mercury",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "David Bowie",
              "Mick Jagger",
              "Bon Jovi"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Freddie Mercury, renowned for his powerful and versatile voice, served as the charismatic lead singer of Queen until his passing."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which artist released the album 'Hot Fuss' in 2004?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Killers",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Arctic Monkeys",
              "Franz Ferdinand",
              "The Strokes"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Hot Fuss' marked The Killers' debut album, gaining commercial success and establishing them as a prominent rock band."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the real name of the artist known as 50 Cent?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Curtis Jackson",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Calvin Broadus",
              "Marshall Mathers",
              "Shawn Carter"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Curtis Jackson, professionally known as 50 Cent, rose to fame as a prominent figure in the hip-hop and rap music industry."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which famous music producer is known for his 'Wall of Sound' technique?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Phil Spector",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Quincy Jones",
              "Rick Rubin",
              "Dr. Dre"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Phil Spector pioneered the 'Wall of Sound,' a dense and layered production style, influencing numerous recording artists and producers."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which singer is known for incorporating whistle register into her songs?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Marian Carey",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Whitney Houston",
              "Celine Dion",
              "Beyoncé"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Mariah Carey's utilization of the whistle register, characterized by soaring and piercing notes, sets her apart as a vocal virtuoso."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the stage name of the Australian singer born Alecia Beth Moore?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Pink",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Katy Perry",
              "Beyoncé",
              "Rihanna"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Alecia Beth Moore adopted the stage name Pink, emerging as a bold and versatile artist renowned for her impactful performances."
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}